"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Team Jiraiya
《綱手 : 異教のマントを
羽織った男が➡
When the man in the strange cloak,
己が腹部に鋭く尖った
金属の棒を突き立てると➡
impaled himself with
his pointed metal weapon,
ナルトは同じ個所に 焼けるような
痛みを感じるのだった》
Naruto felt an excruciating pain...
in the same area of his own body.
((ナルト : クッ…。
(飛段)俺の呪いから
逃げられると思うな。
Don't think you can
escape my curse!
忍の世界は呪われてんだ。
諦めな！
The shinobi world is cursed!
Get over it!
うぅ…。
クハハハ。
なっ！ 分身だと。
What? A Clone?
う ず ま き… ナルト連弾！
Na... Ru... To...
Uzumaki Barrage!
見たか！ うずまきナルト連弾だ。
Did you see that?
It's my Naruto Uzumaki Barrage!
(サスケ)フッ 獅子連弾のモノマネか。
An imitation of my Lions Barrage.
なんだと～！
(サクラ)ケンカしてる場合？
What did you say?
This is not the time to be arguing.
あぁ そうだった。
Oh yeah, that's right...
カカシ先生はどこだ。
Where's Kakashi Sensei?
さあな。 俺たちは雇われて
実験を手伝ってるだけさ。
Who knows?
We were merely hired to help
with the experiment.
実験？
Experiment?
ああ 呪われた忍世界に
希望なんてない➡
Yeah...
To prove that there's no hope
in a cursed shinobi world.
ってことを証明するためのな。
めんどくせえから 手っ取り早く➡
It's a pain...
so I figured I'd give you
the answer real quick, but...
答えを出してやろうと
思ったんだがよ。
え？
どうやら➡
What?
I don't think he's the kind of
opponent you can handle.
お前の手に負える相手じゃ
なさそうだな。
この…。
Why you!
(弥彦)あいや しばらく！
Hey there, long time no see!
我ら妙木山 蝦蟇の精霊仙素道人➡
Trained by the Great Toad Spirit
of Mount Myoboku,
通称 ガマ仙人に鍛えられし➡
also known as the Toad Sage...
雨隠れの徒 三人！ その名も➡
... we are the trio from the Hidden Rain
チーム・ジライヤと見知りおけ。
known as Team Jiraiya,
remember that
and let our presence be known!
(いの)チ チーム…。
(チョウジ)ジライヤ？
T-Team...
Jiraiya?
(シカマル)ジライヤって
まさか伝説の三忍の…。
Jiraiya?
Are you talking about one
of the Legendary Sannin?
(いの)あ あの クールでかっこよくて
流し目がたまらなくて➡
The one who's cool and suave,
with that irresistible
sidelong glance
見つめられると１秒で女の子が
失神しちゃうって噂の!?
that makes a girl fall madly
in love in a second?
(チョウジ)それに
木ノ葉男子全員の憧れの➡
Also the one who's admired by
every guy in the Hidden Leaf
(師匠にしたいランキング１位のあの？))
and who ranks at the top of
the most desired master list?
《なんだ これは。
What the hell is this?!
自来也め
自分のことを美化しすぎだ》
Jiraiya's too full of himself!
((チーム・ジライヤ…。
ま ほんとのところ➡
Team Jiraiya...
Actually, we're called
the "Akatsuki"
暁なんつう いまいちピンとこねえ
名前で呼ばれちゃいるが➡
which isn't too catchy
or cool at all...
俺たち３人は チーム・ジライヤで
お目通り願うぜ。
But just remember the three of us
as Team Jiraiya.
自来也の弟子ってことかよ。
So you're Jiraiya's pupils?
木ノ葉のもんじゃなきゃ➡
Are you implying that only guys
from the Hidden Leaf
自来也先生の教えは受けられない。
そう言いたいのか？
can train under Jiraiya Sensei?
べ 別に そんなこと…。
What? I didn't mean it that way!
(弥彦)気に入らないんだよ
その木ノ葉面。
It really rubs me the wrong way...
When you imply that
we're not shinobi
五大国 五大隠れ里じゃなきゃ
忍にあらずってか？
since we're not from
the Hidden Leaf
and the Five Great Nations
and the Five Hidden Villages?
だから そんなこと言ってねえよ。
Like I said... I didn't say that!
ちっぽけだがよ
雨隠れの俺たちも➡
We're not a big, fancy village...
but guys like us
from the Hidden Rain
どっこい生きてるってことを
あいや 見知りおけってんだよ！
are just as good as you, got it?
Remember that and
let our presence be known!
今まで ずっと ずっとだ。
All this time, the Hidden Leaf,
Stone, Sand, and Cloud
木ノ葉 岩 砂 雲。
気分次第で
お前たちは戦争をおっぱじめ➡
have waged war whenever
they felt like it...
間に挟まれた俺たちは
行き場なく➡
And we got stuck in the middle
with nowhere to go...
ふるさとの大地は
土足で踏みにじられ➡
our homeland got ravaged
and destroyed...
それでもお前らは
俺たちの悔しさに歪んだ顔を➡
All the while, you could care less
about our suffering!
かえりみもしない。
(長門)風遁 烈風掌。
Wind Style! Gale Palm!
うわっ。
But we'll rise up.
だが 俺たちは立ち上がる。
悔しくても顔は歪めねえ。
And we won't let our bitterness
hold us back.
行き場がなくても突き進む。
We'll move forward even
if we have no place to go.
チーム・ジライヤは自由を目指す。
Liberty is Team Jiraiya's goal!
やりたいようにやり返す。
And we'll turn the tables
on you all!
やりたいようにやって
アスマたちを連れ去ったというのか。
And that's why you took
Asuma and the others?!
あんたの渾身のスピーチ それなりに
わからないでもねえが➡
Your passionate speech just now...
I understand where
you're coming from.
アスマを… 木ノ葉の仲間を
さらわれた身じゃ➡
But I don't understand
why you would capture Asuma
いまいち頭に入ってこねえんだよ。
and my comrades
from the Hidden Leaf...
木ノ葉 木ノ葉 木ノ葉
世界は木ノ葉で舞い踊るってか？
The Leaf, The Leaf, The Leaf!
Does the world revolve
around the Hidden Leaf?
冗談じゃねえんだよ！
Give me a break!
こっちだって冗談じゃねえ！
Seriously, give me a break!
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
このっ！ 神からの使徒を
足蹴にしやがって！
Why you—!
You dare to kick
an apostle of god?!
呪われやがれ！
Curse you!
キャーッ！
これは 何だってばよ！
What the hell is this?!
《火遁！ 豪火球の術！》
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
サクラちゃん 大丈夫か!?
Are you okay, Sakura?
サスケ君！ ありがとう！
Thank you Sasuke!
え～っ!?
Whaaat?!
フン… この様子じゃ 他の班も➡
Judging by this,
there's no doubt the other teams
are in the same predicament.
俺たちと同じような目に
あってると思って間違いない。
そうね… どうする？
You're right... so what do we do?
早いところ
合流したほうがよさそうだな。
The sooner we join up with them,
the better.
何か文句あるか？
Any objections?
別に。
N-No...
何なの？
What's going on?
変だよ…
行きたい方向に行けない。
This is weird. We can't go
in the direction we want to.
もしかして
誘導されてるのか？ 俺たち。
It's possible
we're being led astray!
They're not coming after us...
(いの)追ってこない…。
なんで あんなタイミングで
割り込んでくんだよ！
Why did you cut in like that?
I could've offered those kids as
a sacrifice to Lord Jashin,
行きがけの駄賃に ガキどもも
ジャシン様の生け贄にできたのによ。
while I was at it!
It's because we're not
under contract for that
(角都)契約にもない余計なことで
ドジ踏みそうだったからな。
and you were about to mess up.
俺たちの仕事は
班長クラスをとらえるところまでだ。
Our job is simply to capture
team captain-level guys.
We won't earn money
just killing brats.
小僧たちを殺したって
カネにはならない。
世の中カネだけじゃ
ねえだろうが！
The world doesn't revolve
around money.
楽しみもなきゃ
生きてる価値なんかねえっつうの。
What's the use of living
if you can't enjoy life?!
That's a luxury we can't afford.
贅沢は言えない。
どんな活動にだって
先立つものが必要だ。
Every action we take
has a priority.
チェッ！ 世知辛い話だぜ。
That's pretty harsh.
ほらよ。
なっ なんだよ？
Here you go.
What?
そいつは任せた。
You take care of this one.
I'm going to round up the rest
of the captains we've hidden.
隠してある他の班長どもを
回収してくる。
あっ おい！
Hey!
チェッ…。
(赤丸)ワン ワン！
(キバ)ああ 赤丸。
Oh, Akamaru
Yeah, it reeks here with the scent
of Shikamaru and the others.
確かに シカマルたちのニオイが
プンプンしやがる。
他にもニオイが… ３人だ。
I picked up the scent
of three guys.
(ヒナタ)つい今しがたまで
ここで戦闘があったみたい。
It seems like there was fighting
here until just moments ago.
(シノ)戦いながら
移動していったことがわかる。
They moved as they were fighting...
I can tell because...
なぜなら… 彼らは
自分たちの移動した跡を➡
... they left telltale signs
of their movements.
残していってくれたからだ。
Shikamaru and his team are okay...
シカマルたちは無事だ。
血のニオイはしてねえからな。
I don't smell any blood.
ワン… ワン！
Let's hurry after them.
急いで追いかけましょ。
A village...
(いの)集落よ…。
But don't you think
something's not right?
(チョウジ)でも なんか
様子がおかしくない？
(いの)これだけの街なのに➡
Not one sign of anyone in
a settlement this large...
人の気配が
まるでしないじゃない。
It seems they wanted
to lure us here.
あいつら 俺たちをこの集落に
誘導したかったらしいな。
どうする？
ここで 紅班を待つ？
What do we do?
Wait for Team Kurenai here?
ああ… さっきのやつら➡
Yeah... Those guys just now
probably laid out a trap
また仕掛けをして
待ち受けてるに違いねえ。
and are just biding their time.
戦力は多いほど確実だ。
The more of us there are to fight,
the better.
敵の戦力が どれほどのものか
わからない以上➡
We don't have a clue about
the enemy's strength,
まずは 仲間との合流が先だ。
so it's better to join up
with the others first.
チェッ
なんでお前が命令してんだよ。
Why are you the one giving orders?
班長がいなくなった今➡
Our captain's gone.
次に優秀な人間が
判断を下すのが妥当だろう。
Isn't it standard procedure for
the next best-qualified person
to make the decisions?
そうよね アカデミーを
首席で卒業した サスケ君と➡
I agree...
If it's between Sasuke,
who graduated at the top of the class
from the Academy...
... and you, who came in last
in our class,
ビリッケツなのに お情けで卒業した
ナルトじゃあ ね…。
and was only allowed
to graduate out of pity...
Yeah, if your dad wasn't
the Hokage...
ああ 親父が火影でなきゃあな。
なんだと やるか！
What? Wanna fight?!
Now that would be interesting.
I'll prove who's better.
フン おもしろい。
どっちが実力が上か➡
今ここで証明してやろうか。
望むところだ。
There's nothing I'd like better!
Hey, you two!
ちょっと２人とも。
俺の前で二度と そんなこと…。
Never say that again in front of me...
気づかないのか。
え!?
You haven't sensed it yet?
Huh?!
Hey guys! You were all okay?
みんなか 無事だったんだな。
ガイの姿が見えないようだが。
I don't see Guy Sensei.
(リー)ええ ガイ先生は突然
いなくなってしまったんです。
Yes.
Guy Sensei went missing suddenly.
こちらも カカシが姿を消した。
Kakashi Sensei also disappeared.
地中に引きずり込まれたような
跡だけ残してね。
There were signs that showed
he was dragged underground...
Yes, a black rope-like organism tangled
around Sensei
(テンテン)ええ 黒い紐状の生物が
引きずり込んでいった。
and dragged him away!
Yeah! That thing attacked us too.
それよ！
私たちを襲ってきたのも。
(ネジ)敵と接触したのか？
ああ 雇われたと言ってた。
You encountered the enemy?
Yeah...
They claimed to have been hired.
なあ それより
早く助けに行って…。
Hey, let's hurry and rescue them!
Don't be in such a rush.
焦るな。
だってよ。
But—!
ガイが いなくなる直前
地面の下を流れるチャクラを見た。
I saw chakra flowing underground
just before Guy went missing.
チャクラの出どころは
だいたい つかんでいる。
We've pretty much pinpointed
the source of the chakra.
だったら！
Then...
The remaining teams
should be nearby too.
残りの班も
この近くにいるはずだ。
We need to regroup
with every team first...
まずは すべての班と合流して
陣営を整えるのが先決だ。
and set up base camp.
チェッ。
Who knows what's happening
to Sensei and the others
《こんなことしてる間に➡
先生たちが
どんな目にあってるか》
while we're wasting time like this...
First, we need to regroup
with the rest of the teams.
まずは 残りの班と合流し➡
There are a few things
I want to confirm with them.
確認したいことが いくつかある。
Like the status of Asuma and Kurenai.
一つは アスマ 紅が今
どうなっているか？ ってことだ。
ガイは意識を失い… 姿を隠した。
Guy lost consciousness...
and went missing.
The exact same thing happened
with Kakashi.
カカシも まったく同じだな。
Why do you think they
both lost consciousness?
なぜ ２人は
意識をなくしたのでしょう。
Come to think of it...
そういや…
カカシ先生が消える前に➡
Kakashi Sensei was looking at
the Shinobi Ageha butterfly
before he disappeared.
シノビアゲハを見たってばよ。
The powdery scales of
the Shinobi Ageha
おそらく シノビアゲハの鱗粉と➡
and the chakra flowing underground
possibly interacted with each other...
地下を流れるチャクラが
相互に影響し合い…。
There's probably a jutsu
that doesn't work on us,
俺たちには効かず➡
上忍たちだけに効く
なんらかの術にかかったのだろう。
but affects only the jonin.
But the scales of the Shinobi Ageha
aren't toxic.
けど シノビアゲハの鱗粉には
毒性はないのよ。
I don't know how the jutsu works.
術の発動条件は
俺にも わからない。
But, like I mentioned,
there's one more thing I want to verify!
だが さっきも言ったが
確認したいことが もう一つ。
What? That's—!
何!? それは！
Lord Fourth's kunai?
四代目のクナイ!?
え… どういうことだってばよ？
What's going on?
Isn't that the kunai that
you found earlier, Sakura?
あれ さっき サクラちゃんが
拾ったやつじゃねえの？
No...
いや… これは
ガイが落としていったものだ。
This is one that Guy Sensei dropped.
Two jonin dropped the kunai
上忍２人が
とっさのこととはいえ➡
entrusted to them by Lord Fourth
at the spur of the moment...
四代目から預かった クナイを➡
That's hard to believe.
落としていくとは考えづらい…。
So if we figure that the enemy
dropped them intentionally...
敵が あえて
クナイを落としていったと考えると。
It's got to be someone with
considerable knowledge of various jutsu?
多くの術に精通した
相当な手だれか？
It's probably someone who knows
the secret behind Lord Fourth's kunai...
もしくは
四代目のクナイの秘密を知る者。
We'd better hurry and join up
with the other teams fast.
やはり 他の班との合流を
急がねばなるまい。
The tracking team of Kiba,
Shino and Hinata
探索班のキバ シノ ヒナタなら➡
would be able to pinpoint
the location quite accurately.
かなりの確率で
居場所を特定できるはずよ。
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
ああ おそらくな。
And once we know the location,
can we rescue the captains?
居場所がわかったら 助けるの？
No.
いや…
カカシたちの状況がわかりしだい➡
Once we know their situation,
we'll send word back to the village.
里と連絡を取る。
ああ。
Right. We haven't been given
the orders for a rescue.
俺たちに 救助命令は出ていない。
Sticking to the rules again?!
《また 掟かよ。
We don't have time to wait for
reinforcements from the village!
里からの救援なんか
待ってられっか！
I don't care what anyone says.
I'm gonna rescue them.
誰が何てったって
俺は助けにいく！》
Mmm... I smell food.
う～ん 何か
食べ物のニオイがするよ。
How about doing some search
and reconnaissance inside the village?
ねぇ 偵察もかねて
集落の中を探しちゃダメかな？
ダメに決まってるでしょ！
Are you kidding?
That's just looking for trouble.
そんな 火事場泥棒みたいな
真似は…。
I guess you're right...
やっぱり。
シッ。 見ろ。
Shh! Look!
Let's follow.
追ってみよう。
Now Komichi...
(アシタバ)さぁ コミチ
急いでケンタを連れていくよ。
Let's hurry and get Kenta.
Fighting's going to start soon right?
(コミチ)戦いが始まるんでしょ？
If there's a fire, Kenta will die.
火が出たら ケンタが死んじゃう。
Then why'd you leave Kenta?
(アシタバ)だったら なんでケンタを
置いてきちゃったんだよ。
Well, because—!
だって…。
Thank goodness!
It hasn't burned down yet!
よかった まだ燃えてないよ！
Kenta! I'm sorry!
ケンタ ごめんよ。
もう絶対 離さないからね！
I'll never leave you again!
We were just like them
back in the day.
あの頃の俺たちと同じだ。
Caught up in other nations' wars...
他国の戦争にさらされて
怯え 逃げて…。
Running scared...
We didn't want any villagers to
get hurt from our strategy...
(小南)作戦のために 村の人たちに
ケガさせちゃいけないから➡
So we told them all to evacuate...
みんなに
出てってもらったけど…。
Damn it...
クソッ… 今度は俺たちが➡
Now we're no different from the Hidden Leaf
and the Sand from back then...
あの頃の木ノ葉や
砂のようじゃねえかよ！
Komichi! Hurry up!
コミチ 早くして！
We have to run away before
the fighting starts.
逃げないと
戦いが始まっちゃうよ！
Wait, big brother!
待って お兄ちゃん！
Hey... Are you kids from this village?
なぁ お前らこの村の子か？
Please tell us.
Where's everyone else?
ねぇ教えて どうして
他の人たちはいないの？
(２人)うぅ…。
You don't have to be scared.
ああ そんなに怖がらないで。
We're not scary people.
お姉さんたち
怪しい者じゃないから。
Run away, Nagato!
((逃げろ！ 長門！
Hurry! Get away!
逃げるんだ！ 早く！
あ… あぁっ。
Damn it!
(クソッ！))
All right then...
なあ じゃあさ 俺たちみたいに
男２人に 女の子１人の➡
Have you seen a group of
two guys and a girl... just like us?
３人組見なかったかな？
(２人)うぅ…。
Yahiko...!
弥彦！
Nagato...!
長門！
うわぁ～！
(２人)うわぁ～！
(長門)うわぁ～！
うわぁ～！
長門！
Nagato!
Komichi!
コミチ！
Those kids are—!
あの子たちが…。
まずい！
This is bad!
No way... Did I...?
そんな 僕は…。
(２人)わ～っ！
うわっ。
ぐっ。
What was that?
何だ？ あれは。
It's coming from inside the village.
村の中のようだな。
敵か？
Is it the enemy?
Is there a team fighting over there?
どこかの班が
やり合っているというのか。
What's happening inside the village?
村でいったい
何が起きてるんだってばよ。
ワン ワン！
あの方角は…。
That direction is...
... the village marked on the map.
地図にある目的地の村。
The scents of Shikamaru and
the others are coming from that way too.
シカマルたちのニオイも あっちからだ。
うむ すぐ向かうべきだろう。
We should head there immediately.
なぜなら あの土煙は
何か大きな異変が➡
That's because that cloud
of dust is a sign
of something big happening
over there.
起こっていることを
示しているからだ。
What're you doing! Hurry up!
何してんだ？ 急げ！
(シノ)ま 待て。
W-Wait!
You should listen until a person
is done speaking!
人の話は 最後まで聞くべきだ
なぜなら…。
That's because... Hey! Wait!
おいっ 待て！
This is bad.
まずいよ。
あの子たち 助けなくちゃ。
We have to save those kids!
Wait!
待てよ。
(２人)えっ？
We can't. Don't go.
ダメだ 行くな。
(いの)どうして？
Why?
Shikamaru...
(チョウジ)シカマル…。
yumemiru toraburumeikaa
A dreaming troublemaker
hitori de dekiru furi o shite
Acting like he can do everything alone
furueru hiza o daite tsuyogatteru
Pretending to be strong
as he holds his shaking knees still
wagamama kogitsune fuaitaa
Spoiled fox cub fighter
hatenaga uzumaita sekai
In a world swirling with questions
mienai kizuna musunde hashitteku
He ties invisible bonds and keeps on running
mado kara tobasu kamihikouki sora aokute
A paper airplane hurled out of a window into the blue sky
anata ga naitekureta kara tsuyoku nareta no kana
You cried for me, Maybe that's why I grew strong
saa, yaru dake yattemiyou yo
Come on, let's do what we can
kore ga yume demo ii jan
So what if this is a dream?
senobi toka shichattemo ii janai? (oh)
It's okay to push ourselves to the limit, right? (Oh)
i wanna be with you
I  wanna  be  with  you
(go go) yurase emoushon
(Go go) Let your emotions go
(let's go) kitto daijoubu
(Let's go) It will be all right
(go go) aozora no hate made tobashiteyuke
(Go go) Let it fly to the farthest reaches of the blue sky
The siblings fall into the sinkhole,
Team Jiraiya rushes in to help,
< きょうから16代目>
but Shikamaru does not make a move.
<旬の小鉢が大好きな豆助>
We have to do what
we came here to do.
♪～
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Order of Priority."
We can't afford to be indecisive.
≫豆助
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero -
Order of Priority
きょうは今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ？
< その小鉢とは？>